Guide to the William R. and Louise Fielder Sheet Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Series 38. 19th Century Imprints
  - By gone hours: romance Philadelphia: A. Fiot,[1845].New York: W. Dubois ,[1845] (Box 48, Folder 5)
    Words by Hon. Mrs. Norton
  - A boy's best friend is his mother: song and chorus New York: T. B. Harms & Co.,1883 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    Music by Frank Mills
  - I never have been false to thee: a ballad s.l.: E. Ferrett & Co.,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    Music by George P. Morris
  - Darling Nelly Gray: song and chorus Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1856 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    Music by B. R. Hanby
  - Rose Lee, with variations Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1849.New Orleans: W. T. Mayo ,1849 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    Music by Ch. Grobe
    Salut à Washington, or, Gems of the South: six favorite melodies with variations
  - Little Robin tell Kitty I'm coming: song & chorus Cleveland: S. Brainard's Sons,1870 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    Words by Frank Howard
    Lithographer: W. J. Morgan & Co., Lith., Cleveland
  - Maid of Athens: song and chorus Philadelphia: F. A. North & Co.,1875 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - La fille de Madame Angot: opera comique de Ch. Lecocq New Orleans: Louis Grunewald,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    Music by J. B. Frambach
    Angot-Lanciers: Nouveau quadrille des Lanciers
  - The forgotten tryst New York: M. Bancroft,1835 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Adapted and arranged by Julius Metz
    Written by Mrs. Norton
  - The third calisthenic rondo New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1838 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Mary of Castle Cary: a favorite Scotch ballad Baltimore: John Cole,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Written by H. Macniel, Esq.
  - My heart's in the highlands: celebrated Scotch ballad Philadelphia: John F. Nunns,1837 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Composed by Henry Phillips
    Arranged by Sidney Pearson
    Performed by Mr. Pearson
  - My presence still, in calm or storm: romance Philadelphia: A. Fiot,[1840 -1855].New York: W. Dubois ,[1844 -1849] (Box 48, Folder 7)
    The Enchantress
  - Duke of Reichstadt's celebrated waltz Boston: E. H. Wade,[1845 -1860] (Box 48, Folder 8)
    Arranged by Adolphe Forte
  - The highland fling Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,[1845 -1848] (Box 48, Folder 8)
    Composed by Mr. Wagstaff
    Arranged by E. D. Roland
  - Dearest Mae, arranged as an easy rondo Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,[1849 -1852] (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Flow gently sweet Afton: a ballad Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,1838 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    Composed and Arranged by J. E. Spilman
  - The carrier dove: a popular ballad Boston: C. H. Keith,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 8)
    Performed by Mrs. Bailey and Miss Poole
  - Highland Mary: a favorite Scotch ballad Baltimore: John Cole,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Accompaniments by L. Kozeluch
  - The lay of the troubadour New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Music by F. F. Hagen
    Written by E. L. Bulwer
    Renzi
  - Am I to blame Philadelphia: Kretschmar & Nunns,1834 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Composed by James C. Maeder
  - Jock O'Hazeldean: a favorite Scottish ballad Baltimore: John Cole,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Words by Sir Walter Scott
  - Hurrah for the bonnets of the blue: a ballad Baltimore: Geo. Willig,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Performed by Miss Clara Fisher
  - O! Doubt not: song New York: Hewitt,1833 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    Composed and Arranged by Peters
  - The lords of creation men we call: a song Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,1838 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    Adapted and arranged by J. S. R.
  - There grows a bonnie briar bush Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 10)
    Arranged by James Dewar
    Performed by Mrs. Shirreff
  - The moon's on the lake: the celebrated Scotch song of the Macgregors gathering New York: William Hall & Son,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - The Queen's Canadian quadrille Montreal: Henry Prince,n.d. (Box 48, Folder 10)
    Music by Henry Prince
    Lithographer: J. H. Bufford's, Lith. Boston
  - The first kiss Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,[1858 -1876] (Box 49, Folder 1)
    Composed by M. W. Balf
    Poetry by Desmond Ryan
    Lithographer: J. H. Bufford
  - Spring shower: polka Buffalo: J. Sage & Sons,1854 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    Composed by Albert Poppenberg
  - Les bords du Mississippi: variations brillantes New York: William Hall & Son,1853 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    Lithographer: J. C. Pearson
  - The Indianna polka Baltimore: F. D. Benteen,1847.New Orleans: W. T. Mayo ,1847 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    Composed by Francis Buck
    J. C. Pearson
  - The moorish maid s.l.: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - When, when wilt thou meet me: a ballad Boston: Parker & Ditson,[1838 -1842] (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Poetry by J. Halford, Esq.
    Performed by Miss Reynolds
  - Thou wilt go and forget me: ballad Philadelphia: Lo. Meighen & Co.,[1842] (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Written by T. Haynes Bayly
  - Violet mazurka Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,[1844 -1857] (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Composed by E. C. Phelps
  - Bonnie sweet Bessie, the maid of Dundee Boston: White, Smith & Co.,1878 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Music by J. L. Gilbert
    Words by Arabella Root
  - The wave waltz Baltimore: W. C. Peters,1845.Cincinnati: Peters & Co. ,1845 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Arranged by Joseph Tofso
    Also published by W. C. Peters, Louisville.
  - Twilight dews: a favorite song New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1858] (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Meet me in the willow glen Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,[1819 -1850] (Box 49, Folder 3)
    Composed by A. Lee
    Written by Mrs. Cornwall B. Wilson
  - Let us haste to Kelvin grove Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,[1819 -1850] (Box 49, Folder 3)
    Written by John Sim, Esq.
  - Oh silver shining moon Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1850.New York: Gould & Berry ,1850 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    Words and Music by L. V. H. Crosby
    Also published by H. D. Hewitt, New Orleans; G. W. Brainard & Co., Louisville; and C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston. Manuscript verse on back. No author.
  - With faded flowers thy lyre we'll wreathe Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,[1834] (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - The songs of our fathers Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1835 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - 50 select pianoforte studies, part II New York: G. Schirmer,1875 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Music by J. B. Cramer
    Arranged by Dr. Hans von Bulow
    Translated from the German by Albert R. Parsons and B. Boekelman
  - Softly the chimes are ringing: song Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,n.d.Cincinnati: John Church, Jr. ,n.d. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Music by A. Leduc
    Words by G. Lindley
    Also published by W. A. Pond & Co., New York; Lyon & Healy, Chicago; J. C. Haynes & Co., Boston; and C. W. A. Trumpler, Philadelphia.
  - Angels of dawn: grand march s.l.: W. F. Shaw,1878 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Lithographer: W. H. Butler, Lith., Philadelphia
  - Gray rocks and grayer sea Boston: C. W. Thompson & Co.,1900 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Music by Kate Vannah
    Poetry by C. G. D. Roberts
    Engraver Walker; C. F. W. Schlimper, Eng., Boston
  - Musical treasures: illustrated Cleveland: S. Brainard's Sons,1874 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Lithographer: Brainards' Musical Treasures; W. J. Morgan & Co., Cleveland
    Love in youth: ballad / written and arranged by H. B. Farnie --Dancing leaves (La danse des feuilles), opus 18 / music by Tito Mattel --Whisper in hte twilight / words by George May, music by Anthony Nish --Festival galop / music by Charles Coote, Jr. --Forsake me not: sacred song / music by Stephen Glover --Chilperic: quadrille on airs from Herve's opera / music by Charles Godfrey.
    H. B. Farnie; Tito Mattel; George May; Anthony Nish; Charles Coote, Jr.; Stephen Glover; Charles Godfrey
  - Alpine horn grand march Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1852 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Grobe's Parlour Music, Lessons for Ladies
  - Golden beauty waltz New York: William A. Pond & Co.,[1863 -1877] (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Charles Godfrey
    Lithographer: New England Lith. Co., Boston
  - Maud waltz New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1863.Boston: Koppitz, Prufer & Co. ,1863 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Music by J. Levy
    Also published by C. Y. Fonda, Cincinnati; M. Gray, San Francisco; L. Grunewald, New Orleans; H. N. Hempsted, Milwaukee; and H. Prince, Montreal.
  - Gipsy girl's dream (I dreamt that I dwelt in marble halls) New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1858] (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Composed by J. M. W. Balfe
    Performed by Miss Louisa Pyne
    The Bohemian girl
  - Where, where is the rover s.l.: s.d.,n.d. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    Poetry by W. R. Addison
  - Three bells polka New York: S. T. Gordon & Son,1863 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    Six favorite polkas for the drawing room
  - Girls, get a home of your own New York: Henry Tucker,1866 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    Words by Josephine Pollard
    Performed by Mrs. Marie Abbott
  - The Tyrolese hunter: a song (Gramachree Molly) London: D'Almaine & Co.,n.d. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    Composed by Madame Maliban de Beriot
    Lithographer: J. Graf, Printer to her Majesty
    Performed by Madame Maliban de Beriot
    Illustrated Songs, Ballads, & Duets, No. 8
  - Hawthorn schottische Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1857 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    Composed by J. Travis Quigg
  - Twinkle, twinkle, little star, or, Meet me at the bars [two copies] Boston: White, Smith & Company,1879 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    Words and Music by Frel Mac Evoy
    Arranged by J. M. Navoni
    Performed by Miss Julia Wilson and Mr. Ignacio Martinetti
    Joshua Whitcomb
  - The old curiosity shop: polka mazurka Pittsburgh: H. Kleber & Bro.,[1864] (Box 49, Folder 7)
    Composed by R. Bukowitz
  - The Masonic schottisch, with introduction New York: William Hall & Son,1855 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    Composed by J. A. Fowler
  - Pan-American Congress march Chicago: Mational Music Co.,1889 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    Composed by Bernard Bloss
  - The departure for Syria (Partant pour la Syrie): romance Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1855.New Orleans: H. D. Hewitt ,1855 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    Composed by Madame Hortense
    Also published by D. A. Truax, Cincinnati; S. T. Gordon, New York; J. E. Gould, Philadelphia; and C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston.
  - Darling!: descriptive song New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1873 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    Words and Music by Harrison Millard
    Verse manuscript on inside cover.
  - Say not farewell: song New York: Spear & Dehnhoff,1877 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    Written and composed by Harrison Millard
  - Swinging in the lane Brooklyn: Sawyer & Thompson,[1862].New York: William A. Pond & Co. ,[1862] (Box 49, Folder 8)
    Also published by Oliver Ditson & Co., Boston; Lee & Walker, Philadelphia; and Skinner & Sperry, New Haven.
  - Ossian's serenade Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1850.New York: J. E. Gould & Co. ,1850 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Waiting song for soprano or tenor: violin or flute obligato New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1867.Chicago: Chicago Music Co. ,1867 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    Words by E. H. Flagg
    Also published by H. N. Hempsted, Milwaukee; M. Gray, San Francisco; H. Kleber & Bro., Pittsburgh; and Ludden & Bates, Savannah.
  - Waiting song for soprano or tenor: violin or flute obligato New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1867 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Dreaming of home and mother: song and chorus Boston: G. D. Russell & Co.,1868.San Francisco: M. Gray ,1868 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    Poetry and music by John P. Ordway, M.D.
    Also published by C. C. DeZouche, Montreal.
  - Love among the roses Boston: G. D. Russell & Co.,1869.St. Louis: Kunkel Bros. ,1869 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    Words by W. H. Delehanty
    E. N. Catlin's songs
    Also published by Jas. N. Davis, Portland.
  - The light of other days is faded: ballad Baltimore: Geo. Willig,n.d. (Box 49, Folder 9)
    The Maid of Artois
  - Watching and waiting Philadelphia: F. A. North & Co.,1873 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Words and Music by J. Ford
  - The silver moon: song and chorus Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1847.New York: William Hall & Son ,1847 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Arranged by Jos. W. Turner
    Performed by Park quartette club
  - Pretty as a picture: song and chorus Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1876.New York: C. H. Ditson & Co. ,1876 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Lithographer: C. H. Bufford's Sons, Lith., Boston
    Also published by Lyon & Healy, Chicago; J. C. Hayes & Co., Boston; and J. E. Ditson & Co., Philadelphia.
  - The day when you forget me: ballad Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1876.New York: C. H. Ditson & Co. ,1876 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Words by Morgan
  - In happier hours, melodies of various nations Boston: G. P. Reed & Co.,[1850 -1852] (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Symphonies and accompaniments by Henry R. Bishop
  - Going home!: ballad and chorus, companion to home delights Boston: J. P. Ordway,1855.New York: Horace Waters ,1855 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Poetry and music by John P. Ordway
    Performed by Ordway's aeolians
    Also published by E. L. Walker, Philadelphia.
  - O'er the ear blue mountain: ballad Baltimore: John Cole,1833 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Music by G. F. Cole
  - Good bye!: a ballad Boston: John Ashton & Co.,[1834] (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Written and adapted by W. Jas. D.
  - The woodbine bower Philadelphia: Kretschmar & Nunns,[1834 -1836] (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Composed and Arranged by G. A. Hodson
    Performed by Sigr. Begrez
  - The recall: a ballad New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1832] (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Composed and Arranged by Mrs. Hemans's sister
  - As the robin when once fondly cherished: a ballad Boston: Parker & Ditson,[1838 -1842] (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Words by G. E. Inman
  - Are we almost there?: a touching ballad Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1845 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Written and composed by Florence Vane
  - Love not! New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1858] (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Composed by Blockley
  - Only a dream of home: solo, duett & chorus Boston: White, Smith, & Company,1874.Chicago: The Root & Sons Music Co. ,1874 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Also published by Wm. A. Pond & Co., New York; A. J. Boucher, Montreal; Patten & Wheelden, Bangor; M. Gray, San Francisco; and L. K. Hammer.
  - Do they miss me at home? Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1853.Philadelphia: J. E. Gould ,1853 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Performed by The Amphions
    Also published by C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston; A. A. Adey, Springfield; D. A. Traux, Cincinnati; T. T. Barker, Boston; and T. S. Berry, New York.
  - Do they think of me at home?: ballad Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,[1858 -1876].Cincinnati: John Church, Jr. ,[1858 -1876] (Box 50, Folder 3)
    Music by C. W. Glover
    Also published by Firth, Pond & Co., New York; J. E. Gould, Philadelphia; J. C. Haynes & Co., Boston.
  - The home I love so well Boston: Parker & Ditson ,1839 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    Composed by E. L. White
  - Welcome home: a companion to 'Do they miss me at home?' Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1853.Philadelphia: J. E. Gould ,1853 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    Music by C. C. Converse
  - Outward bound: a song Boston: Parker & Ditson ,[1838 -1842] (Box 50, Folder 3)
    Written and composed by Hon. Mrs. Norton
  - I wandered on the sea-boat shore, or, the Shells of ocean New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1852].Boston: George P. Reed & Co. ,[1848 -1852] (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Lizzy Lindsay, or, Will you gang to the highlands wi' me: an admired old highland song Boston: C. Bradlee,[1827 -1844] (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Arranged by A. Robertson
  - She sleeps in the valley Boston: E. H. Wade,1846 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Words by J. Simmonds Davis
    Melodies of the Harmoneons arranged for the piano forte
  - Sweet sympathy: a favorite song translated from the French New York: Firth & Hall,1843.New York: James L. Hewitt & Co. ,1843 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Music by A. J. Morales
  - Silvery shower: tremolo etude Boston: Henry Tolman & Co.,1854 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Composed by Adolph Baumbach
  - Where the bright waves are dashing: duett Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1851 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Written and composed by Marion Dix Sullivan
  - How softly on the bruised heart Cleveland: S. Brainard,1849 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    Composed by Charles Slade
  - Our little ones: solo duett trio and quartette Rochester: Gibbons & Stone,1882 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    Music by George W. Dixson
  - As upon a summer river Boston: William H. Oakes,1842.Boston: John Ashton ,1842 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    Music by Harold
    Words by O. W. Withington, Esq.
    Sabbath evenings: a collection of original and selected airs arranged for one, two, three & four voices
  - Homeward bound!: a ballad Boston: C. Bradlee,1831 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Sweet summer days have come once more St. Louis: Bollman & Schatzman,[1867].Philadelphia: G. Andre; & Co. ,[1867] (Box 50, Folder 5)
    Composed by J. C. Meininger
    Words by Thomas B. Long
    Also published by Fischer & Bro., Dayton.
  - The witches flight: galop caprice Boston: White, Smith & Co.,1875.New York: Spear & Denhoff ,1875 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Music by H. M. Russell
    Lithographer: I. L. A. Brodersen & Co., San Francisco
  - Robin Adair: Scotch song in 'La dame blanche' Philadelphia: L. Meyer,1865.: (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Arranged by L. M.
    Lithographer: F. Moras, Lith., Philadelphia
    Performed by Mr. Habelmann
  - My mother dear: ballad New York: Davis & Horn,1839.: (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Written and composed by Samuel Lover, Esq.
  - Bohemian air: with variations Philadelphia: A. Fiot,[1844 -1849].New York: W. Dubois ,[1844 -1849] (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Music by Ch. Czerny
    Germany: 6 popular airs arranged and fingered for the piano forte
  - Nellie lost and found Chicago: Root & Cady,1861.Cleveland: S. Brainard ,1861 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Also published by Russell & Tolman, Boston and H. N. Hempsted, Milwaukee.
  - Bochsa's celebrated march, describing the advance and repeal of a military band New York: C. T. Geslain,n.d. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    Arranged by S. T. Rosenberg
  - My ain fire side: a celebrated song Boston: John Ashton,[1824 -1833] (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Marching thro' Georgia grand march Cleveland: S. Brainard's Sons,1875 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Les voix du matin: morceau pour le piano Boston: Earl Prufer,1869.New York: William A. Pond & Co. ,1869 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Will you come to my mountain home Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1845 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    Performed by The Orphean family
  - Morning's ruddy beam: song of the alpine hunters New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1839.London: T. E. Purday ,1839 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    Written and composed by George Linley, Esq.
  - Oh, how long the day: air of three notes Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1836 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    Written and composed by Jean Jacques Rousseau
    Adapted by C. H. S.
  - May'st thou be happy Philadelphia: Kretschmar & Nunns,1834 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - A smile for the many who smile on us: a song Boston: C. Bradlee,1840 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    Words and Music by O. W. Withington
  - Some one rocking baby: waltz-song and chorus St. Louis: Henry Bollman & Sons,1883 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    Music by H. Nilsson
    Words by Samuel Callan
  - The old wooden rocker: a family song New York: T. B. Harms & Co.,1888 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    Written and composed by Florence Harper
  - Gentle ray of sunlight: song Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,[1858 -1876].New York: Firth, Pond & Co. ,[1858 -1876] (Box 50, Folder 9)
    Also published by J. Church, Jr., Cincinnati; J. C. Haynes & Co., Boston; C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston; and J. E. Gould, Philadelphia.
  - A boy's best friend is his mother Cleveland: S. Brainard's Sons, Publishers,1884.Chicago: S. Brainard's Sons, Publishers ,1884 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    Words and Music by Ben Williams
    Lithographer: Goes & Quencel, Lith., Chicago
    Home favorites: vocal
  - Come, with thy lute, to the fountain: duett adapted to a favorite German air with a piano forte accompaniment Boston: George F. Reed,n.d. (Box 50, Folder 9)
    Adapted by J. P. Hullah
  - Titus march Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,n.d. (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Potpourri from Olivette: opera comique New York: S. T. Gordon & Son,1881 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    Arranged by W. A. Fallman
  - I am waiting, Essie dear: song and chorus Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1877 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    Music by George W. Brown
  - Serenade à Marie: pensée romantique Cincinnati: A. C. Peters & Bro.,1864.St. Louis: J. L. Peters & Bro. ,1864 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - The waltz rondo New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1832] (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - The harp at midnight: nocturne Chicago: Lyon & Healy,1866.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1866 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    Composed by V. B. Aubert
    Also published by T. Firth, New York; C. W. A. Trumpler, Philadelphia; J. Church, Jr., Cincinnati; and Western News Service, Chicago.
  - Five belles polka New York: S. T. Gordon & Son,1863 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Savourneen Deelish: an Irish melody arranged for the guitar Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - ÔTis the last rose of summer, with an introduction and variations Louisville: W. C. Peters & Co.,[1849 -1852].Cincinnati: Peters & Field ,[1849 -1852] (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Xarifa, or, The bridal of Andallo Baltimore: J. Cole & Son,[1834 -1836] (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Music by Mrs. Robert Arkwright
    Written by John Lockhart, Esq.
  - When the tide comes in: descriptive song for soprano or tenor Boston: G. D. Russell & Company,1873 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Written by H. Ashland Kean
    Lithographer: Gurney & Son, New York; W. F. Walker, Boston
    Harrison Millard's latest songs
  - When the tide comes in: descriptive song for soprano or tenor Boston: G. D. Russell & Company,1876.Providence: Cory Bros. ,1876 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Lithographer: Armstrong & Co., Lith., Boston; Riverside Press, Cambridge
    Also published by McCurrie, Weber, & Co., San Francisco.
  - United: answer to waiting song for soprano or tenor New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1874.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1874 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Words by Nellie Littleton
    Also published by H. Kleber & Bro., Pittsburgh; H. N. Hempsted, Milwaukee; Lee & Walker, Philadelphia; and J. T. Wamelink, Cleveland.
  - When a child I roamed the green fields through: a song New York: Atwill,1845 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Words and Music by Stephen C. Massett
    Performed by Miss Mary Taylor and Mrs. Bailey
  - Return to me again: a very popular ballad New York: Atwill's,1843.New Orleans: Charles Horst ,1843 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Written and composed by Georgina J. Morinski
  - The infants slumber: arranged and adapted to a popular southern refrain New York: Atwill,1838 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Arranged and adapted by J. Watson
    Poetry by Jonas B. Phillips, Esq.
    Performed by Miss Clarence Wells
  - Old King Time!: a ballad New York: Atwill,1841 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - The land we live in: a partiotic song New York: Atwill,1845 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Composed and Arranged by E. Woolf
    Performed by Mr. H. G. Sherman
  - Syracuse polka New York: Jollie,1848 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Composed and Arranged by J. A. Fowler
  - The pastor's daughter: a rural ballad New York: Atwill,1844 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Never let the heart for sorrows grieve: an admired duett New York: Atwill,1845 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Composed by Balfe
    Performed by Mrs. Seguin and Mr. Frazier
    Balfe's celebrated opera 'Bohemian Girl'
  - Twenty years ago: a ballad New York: Atwill,1841 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Performed by Mrs. Hardwick, Mrs. Bailey, and Mr. A. Phillips
  - My boy Tammy: a favorite Scotch ballad New York: Atwill,[1834 -1847] (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Potpourri from Olivette: opera comique Boston: G. D. Russell,1881 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Music by Audran
    Arranged by Ernest Leslie
  - Dinna forget Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,[1835] (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Words by Mrs. Philip Millard
  - Moonbeams on the lake: fantasia for the piano New York: W. F. Shaw & Co.,1903 (Box 51, Folder 4)